<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Charles&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>http://mims.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Charles&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Charles Mims 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 13:07:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mims.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming in Scala</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2017/07/functional-programming-in-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 13:07:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2017/07/functional-programming-in-scala/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just completed the first course in the coursera scala specialization series of courses, Functional Programming Principles in Scala.
I&amp;rsquo;m not going to lie, it&amp;rsquo;s a tough course that challenged my hack-it-together python background. My python workflow goes something like this:
Using sublimetext, write a function that takes some object, usually a list or dict, some strings or ints, etc., and return a dict or list, etc. Copy that function and paste it in ipython.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 14:09:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a 37yo DevOps/dev/sysadmin/geek living in Bastrop, Texas which is about 45 minutes east of Downtown Austin where I&amp;rsquo;m the DevOps guy at a small startup that does social media analytics to help companies make sense of mountains of data. I have a lovely intellectual and feisty wife, an opinionated 2yo girl and a boy due any day now. I love exploring new technology, cooking, and DIY projects.
Some tech I either use daily or am interested in: python, scala, golang, docker, kubernetes, mesos, elasticsearch, cassandra, aerospike, postgres, macos, ios, machine learning, opencv, raspberry pi, networking, debian/ubuntu, coreos</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling an API with go</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2017/01/calling-an-api-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 10:25:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2017/01/calling-an-api-with-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to learn go (golang) over the past couple months. The documentation at golang.org is fantastic and only takes about a half a day to get through, but I&amp;rsquo;m still working on getting really comfortable thinking in go. Coming from python, I find the language beautiful, but not quite natural. I&amp;rsquo;m getting there.
I wrote this little program to fetch the latest bitcoin price from the coinbase API and print it to stdout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bitcoin!</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2016/11/bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 12:42:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2016/11/bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of a thing called bitcoin. &amp;ldquo;It uses blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s awesome!&amp;rdquo; Right? But what is it? Why should you use it? How can you get started?
Check out bitcoin.org/en and you&amp;rsquo;ll see a concise explanation: &amp;ldquo;Bitcoin uses peer-to-peer technology to operate with no central authority or banks; managing transactions and the issuing of bitcoins is carried out collectively by the network. Bitcoin is open-source; its design is public, nobody owns or controls Bitcoin and everyone can take part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>encrypting text with gpg</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2016/11/encrypting-text-with-gpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 16:29:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2016/11/encrypting-text-with-gpg/</guid>
      <description>This post is a quick-start guide to using gpg to encrypt and decrypt text for messages via email, slack, or just about any medium. My gpg key is F930E099 at the end of this post. Read on for more details about how to use it!
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been paying attention to this year&amp;rsquo;s Presidential campaign, you&amp;rsquo;re probably aware of the impact that leaked emails can have on one&amp;rsquo;s public image. The thing that I&amp;rsquo;m surprised I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard anyone talking about is not whether it was a private email server or a government-secured server, but that any emails, not to mention classified material, are sent via unencrypted email.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>