<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on mims.io</title>
    <link>http://mims.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on mims.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Charles Mims 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 11:38:19 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mims.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sapien</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2018/04/sapien/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 11:38:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2018/04/sapien/</guid>
      <description>The other night my wife and I were talking about an idea I had for a blockchain-based social media site that took the best things about reddit, but ran distributed on users&amp;rsquo; systems via blockchain, where people could buy credits and donate fractions of credits to content creators, and communities could form about geographies and interests, using the platform for news, discussion, community engagement, and just staying in touch with old friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Belt Tensioner Pulley for Samsung Dryer</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2018/04/improved-belt-tensioner-pulley-for-samsung-dryer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 22:41:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2018/04/improved-belt-tensioner-pulley-for-samsung-dryer/</guid>
      <description>I had the terrible misfortune of buying a Samsung dryer with one critical design flaw and several annoying flaws that aren&amp;rsquo;t apparent in the store. The critical flaw is the belt tensioner pulley which has a metal-on-metal bearing that wears out after about a year. The first time it happened I replaced it, hoping that the replacement part with the quality grease I used would last longer. It didn&amp;rsquo;t. This time around, I decided something more extreme was in order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacOS Tweaks for Developers</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2018/04/macos-tweaks-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 11:38:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2018/04/macos-tweaks-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled across a bug yesterday that managed to screw up my filesystem around my homedir (hard links to parent directories, anyone?), so I took the opportunity to re-image my laptop and set it up anew. While getting all the little settings the way I like them, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d write them down here so others may benefit. If you&amp;rsquo;re using a mac for development, these are just a few applications and configuration settings that I like that you might like as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get docker-maven-plugin to work with docker native on macos</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2017/09/get-docker-maven-plugin-to-work-with-docker-native-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 11:41:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2017/09/get-docker-maven-plugin-to-work-with-docker-native-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>Get docker-maven-plugin to work with docker native on macos.
$ mvn version ^C[11:09:43] cmims@MBP:~$ mvn -version Apache Maven 3.5.0 (ff8f5e7444045639af65f6095c62210b5713f426; 2017-04-03T14:39:06-05:00) Maven home: /Users/cmims/apache-maven-3.5.0 Java version: 1.8.0_144, vendor: Oracle Corporation Java home: /Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/jdk1.8.0_144.jdk/Contents/Home/jre Default locale: en_US, platform encoding: UTF-8 OS name: &amp;quot;mac os x&amp;quot;, version: &amp;quot;10.12.6&amp;quot;, arch: &amp;quot;x86_64&amp;quot;, family: &amp;quot;mac&amp;quot; $ docker version Client: Version: 17.06.2-ce API version: 1.30 Go version: go1.8.3 Git commit: cec0b72 Built: Tue Sep 5 20:12:06 2017 OS/Arch: darwin/amd64 Server: Version: 17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>blacklisting mbeans from Cassandra in jxm_exporter</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2017/09/blacklisting-mbeans-from-cassandra-in-jxm_exporter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 11:50:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2017/09/blacklisting-mbeans-from-cassandra-in-jxm_exporter/</guid>
      <description>Why: There is a bug in Cassandra v3.0.14 that was preventing cleanup of sstables while tombstones were being polled. https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-13752
As I understand it, this is happening because the method that cleans them up and the method that reports the metrics step on eachother&amp;rsquo;s feet &amp;ndash; getting metrics on tombstones interrups the cleanup and corrupts the table. It&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be fixed in 3.0.15 due next week, but disabling the polling of this mbean should stop the badness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>simple API call with go</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2017/01/simple-api-call-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 10:25:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2017/01/simple-api-call-with-go/</guid>
      <description>I like to familiarize myself with emerging and popular technologies so that when I come to a new problem I have more options in my bag of tricks to solve it as well as possible. Tools. I like tools.
Go is an increasingly popular language with a large dedicated following. Most of the new and amaze-balls infrastructure tech is written in go, including docker, etcd, prometheus, kubernetes. There are even tensorflow bindings and great distributed computing options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bitcoin!</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2016/11/bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 12:42:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2016/11/bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of a thing called bitcoin. &amp;ldquo;It uses blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s awesome!&amp;rdquo; Right? But what is it? Why should you use it? How can you get started?
Check out bitcoin.org/en and you&amp;rsquo;ll see a concise explanation: &amp;ldquo;Bitcoin uses peer-to-peer technology to operate with no central authority or banks; managing transactions and the issuing of bitcoins is carried out collectively by the network. Bitcoin is open-source; its design is public, nobody owns or controls Bitcoin and everyone can take part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>encrypting text with gpg</title>
      <link>http://mims.io/2016/11/encrypting-text-with-gpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 16:29:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mims.io/2016/11/encrypting-text-with-gpg/</guid>
      <description>This post is a quick-start guide to using gpg to encrypt and decrypt text for messages via email, slack, or just about any medium. My gpg key is F930E099 at the end of this post. Read on for more details about how to use it!
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been paying attention to this year&amp;rsquo;s Presidential campaign, you&amp;rsquo;re probably aware of the impact that leaked emails can have on one&amp;rsquo;s public image. The thing that I&amp;rsquo;m surprised I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard anyone talking about is not whether it was a private email server or a government-secured server, but that any emails, not to mention classified material, are sent via unencrypted email.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>